

Scrum Master

Contact

Location Delhi

**Phone** 9773877594

## E-mail

Swarnima2mn@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/i n/swarnima-raj-12bb07147

Skills

Customer interaction

Quality Assurance

Documentation Management

Problem-Solving

Planning & Coordination

Teambuilding

Organization & Time Management

Solutions Driven Scrum Master & Software Quality Assurance with over 4 years of experience collaborating with various cross functional teams in designing, documenting and delivery of Process innovations driving the attainment of business goals. Seek opportunities to transform the organization's Product into fresh costeffective solution leading to more efficient Operations.

## **Work History**

#### 2020-04 -Current

#### Scrum Master

## Tata Consultancy Services, Pune

- Assessed each scrum team member's responsibilities and delegated tasks to balance each employee's workload.
- Coached teams in Agile practices and provided necessary training to create positive mindset to Agile methodologies.
- Provided extensive guidance on Agile scrum processes and methodologies to highly effective teams with goals of improving quality and productivity.
- Planned Agile best practices and encouraged team cohesion, overcoming impediments and hurdles to productivity.
- Shielded scrum team from external interference for optimal productivity and success of Agile process.
- Managed product backlog and supported Scrum framework for monthly sprint releases.
- Collaborated with product owners, team members, technologists and other scrum masters to define solutions and drive progress.
- Led sprint reviews, daily scrums and planning meetings to realize full team engagement.
- Proactively identified and found ways to resolve issues to prevent distractions and keep projects on track.
- Facilitated Scrum framework sprint planning, backlog grooming, daily scrums, sprint reviews and sprint retrospectives.
- Closely collaborated with project members to identify and quickly address problems.
- Managed and motivated project teams to promote collaboration and keep members on-task and productive.

## 2018-03 – 2020-04

#### QA Role

## Tata Consultancy Services, Gurugram

- Provided regular updates to team leadership on quality metrics by communicating consistency problems or production deficiencies.
- Wrote and optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing with consistent, thorough approaches.
- Evaluated function, performance and design compliance of every product against design standards and customer needs.
- Identified and tracked defects and supported developers in resolving problems by completing additional tests.
- Utilized Agile software development methods to increase team efficiency.
- Monitored resolution of bugs, tested fixes and helped developers tackle ongoing problems by providing QA perspective.
- Documented testing procedures for developers and future testing use.
- Tailored testing procedures to obtain data most relevant to understanding underlying causes of production limitations.

# Education

2013-2017

B. Tech: ECE

UIT Allahabad (affiliated to Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam University)

# Accomplishments

2020-04 – Current

- Awarded by CVS a Certificate of appreciation for being a role model to my colleagues and for commitment and dedication towards my work.
- Awarded "on the spot (Team) award by Woodside client for Leading the whole project successfully.
- Batch topper in B-Tech
- 3rd Rank Holder in Robotryst -2015.
- Organized cultural fest at college level.

# Certifications

2022-01 Foundation of Project Management
2020-05 Fundamental of Business Analysis
2020-02 Scrum Fundamentals
2020-04 Agile Scrum Trainings